saga.co.uk 2019-04-24

# Saga Group Data Protection Privacy Policy - Saga

### This is the standard data protection privacy policy for the Saga Group.

When it comes to your privacy we never compromise. We will always be clear about why we need the details we ask for, and ensure your personal information is kept as secure as possible. How we do this is explained below.

**Last updated: May 2018**

  * Introduction
  * How we use your information (including fraud prevention & credit checks)
  * Fraud Prevention and Credit Checks
  * Lawful bases for using your information
  * Sharing your information (including information sent outside the European Economic Area – EEA)
  * Keeping you informed about our products and services
  * Amendment and retention of information
  * Your rights
  * Updates to our Privacy Policy and your comments
  * Use of Cookies

### Introduction

The Saga Group, together with its subsidiaries are registered as data controllers with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

Companies within the Saga Group (“Saga”) use a variety of well-known brand and trading names including, but not limited to, Saga, Titan Travel, Saga Healthcare, Claimfast, Metromail and Saga Possibilities (our Membership scheme). Details of the relevant companies can be obtained from the Data Protection Officer via post; The Saga Building, Enbrook Park, Sandgate, Kent CT20 3SE or email; [data.protection@saga.co.uk](mailto:data.protection@saga.co.uk).

Saga ("we","us") are committed to protecting your privacy. We comply with the principles of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and associated data protection legislation. We aim to maintain best-practice standards in our processing of personal and/or special category personal data (this is also referred to as sensitive personal data).

**Back to top**

### How we use your information

We use the information we receive from you, together with information we have obtained from our dealings with you (including in relation to goods and/or services we provide to you and/or your use of those goods and/or services), to provide goods and/or services that you request, to communicate with you, and to personalise information sent to you. Examples of how we may personalise information include using your information in generating an insurance quote for you, working out which departure airports are near to you, or when we will be delivering certain products in your area.

We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others.

We store all the information you provide to us, including information provided via forms you complete on our website, and information which we may collect from your browsing. Our server, in common with nearly all web servers, logs each page that is downloaded from the site. If you contact us electronically we may collect your electronic identifier, e.g. Internet protocol (IP) address or phone number supplied by your service provider. This is to identify the number of visits to our websites, fraudulent behaviour or mystery shoppers using our websites.

Our website may also use SessionCam for analysis. SessionCam is a product that has been developed by SessionCam LTD. SessionCam may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Data collected by SessionCam from the Saga website is for the Saga Group’s internal use only. The information collected is used to improve our website usability and is stored and used for aggregated and statistical reporting. 

For further information; please see our ‘Use of Cookies section’.

We ask for your home, mobile phone number, and email address to enable us to contact you in relation to an enquiry you have made, to contact you if there is a problem with your order, notifying you about important functionality changes to the website, or if there is another genuine reason for doing so. For example, when you enter a contest or other promotional features, we use these details to administer the contest and notify winners.

Sometimes we may need to collect information that the law defines as special category data (also called sensitive personal data). This includes, but is not limited to, information about racial or ethnic origin, sexual orientation, health data, and criminal records. We will not collect or use these types of data without your consent, unless the law allows us to do so. If we do, it will only be when it is necessary as determined by the law and the ICO.

Any new information you provide to us may be used to update an existing record we hold for you. If you provide a work email address we will not be responsible for third parties having access to any communications we send.

We collect credit or debit card details from you in order to pay for a service or product. We will keep such details secure and ensure that the details are only used further with your consent and/or for the purposes of any appropriate refunds.

In the event of phone calls from you, we also reserve the right to ask security questions (which we in our sole discretion deem appropriate) in order to satisfy ourselves that you are who you say you are.

**Back to top**

### Fraud Prevention and Credit Checks

To help us prevent fraud and money laundering, your details may be submitted to fraud prevention agencies and other organisations where your records may be searched. We will also conduct a search with a credit reference bureau to assist us in providing a quote, and to check which payment options we can make available to you. A copy of this search will be left on your credit file but will not affect your credit score. Where we are providing a motor insurance quotation this search will be noted on your credit file and may be reflected in your credit score.

In order to assess financial and insurance risk, we will make full and open checks on the electoral roll registers and public data provided to us by credit reference bureaus and other third parties. This is also to assess your premium at quote and renewal, for credit applications and to assist with identity checks in order to prevent money laundering.

If you apply for other financial services and/or products, a check of your details with fraud prevention agencies may be necessary. The precise nature of these processes is explained fully when you apply.

Our own security procedures mean that we may occasionally have to request proof of identity or check your presence on the electoral roll.

**Back to top**

### Lawful bases for using your information

Before you provide any data to us we will endeavour to make it clear why we need it. Sometimes we may need special category (sensitive) personal data, for example we may require details of any motoring convictions to ensure the insurance price we provide to you is accurate or we may need medical information if you ask us to book an easy access room due to a disability. When this is required, we will obtain your consent first, unless the information is necessary to provide the insurance product or service requested by you. Without this information, we may not be able to fulfil the product or service you have requested.

A customer may properly give their partner's consent over the phone or via the website providing the customer confirms they have permission to do so. If the consent is written, the spouse must independently endorse such consent via counter signature.

We use the information you provide to us, either orally or in writing and the information we obtain from you through the use of our website, and as a result of our dealings with you (including any data we obtain from third parties) to provide the service requested by you. It may also be used for market research, offering renewals and statistical purposes. This also includes pricing insurance risk.

We recognise that we have a legitimate interest in processing the personal data we collect about you for a number of reasons, including, but not limited to: marketing purposes, to enables us to enhance, modify, personalise, or otherwise improve our services, identify and prevent fraud, enhance and protect the security of our network and systems, and market research (e.g. determining the effectiveness of campaigns and the products / services we offer). “Legitimate interests” means the interests of our company in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service and most secure experience.

When we use your information for our legitimate interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you and your data protection rights. Where applicable, legitimate interest assessments are conducted to ensure that these rights are protected.

### Keeping you informed about our products and services

When you contact us, either online or via one of our contact centres, we may ask for your permission to contact you about the products and services we offer. Where we have obtained your permission to do so we will contact you by post, telephone, email or other means to tell you about offers, products and services that may be of interest to you.

We also recognise that it is in our legitimate interests to send communications about our products and services, latest offers and rewards, so we may process your information to send you communications that are tailored to your interests.

At any time, you can opt out of receiving such information, revise the products you would like to hear about or change the method we use to communicate with you. You can update these preferences by calling us on 0800 092 3665 or by visiting [www.mysaga.co.uk](http://www.mysaga.co.uk/).

We also use your personal information to make decisions about what products, services and offers we think you may be interested in. This is called profiling for marketing purposes. You can contact us at any time and ask us to stop using your personal information this way. If you allow it, we may show or send you marketing material online (on our own and other websites including social media), or by email, phone or post.

We make outbound phone calls for a number of reasons relating to our many products, including breakdown cover and insurance. We are fully committed to the regulations set out by Ofcom and follow strict processes to ensure we comply with them.

We may use personal data, collected in respect of one product to market another product that we may deem appropriate and relevant to you based on the information we have collected.

If you make a donation to the Saga Charitable Trust, your data will not be used for marketing purposes.

**Back to top**

### Sharing your information 

As previously mentioned, we do not sell, trade or rent your information, and will never disclose information about you (including information obtained from our dealings with you) to third parties, except:

a) where we have a legal interest in a company;

b) to fulfil your specific orders for a product or service or information in the event that third parties deliver the relevant product or service or information. In these instances, while the information you provide will be disclosed to them, it will only be used for the administration of the service provided, including (but not limited to), verification of any quote given to you, claims processing, underwriting, pricing purposes as appropriate, testing, and to maintain management information for business analysis. For example, if you go on a holiday with us, the hotel needs to know who you are. If you take out an insurance policy provided by a third party, they will need your details in order to administer the policy, verify the quote given to you and process any claims. For further details about how your insurer handles your information, please see their Privacy Policy which can be found on their website. See your schedule policy documentation for your insurer contact details;

c) where third parties administer part or all of the product or service; and

d) for underwriting, pricing, insurance rating analysis and testing purposes, and to maintain management information for business analysis.

We may of course be obliged by law to pass on your information to the police or any other statutory or regulatory authority and in some cases, exemptions may apply under relevant data protection legislation, whereby we can legitimately release personal data e.g. to prevent or detect crime or in connection with legal proceedings.

Subsequent to your purchase of a product or service, we may enter into an arrangement for that service to be provided by a new third party. If this happens, the terms and conditions of your contract with us will provide that you consent to the transfer and processing of personal and/or special category personal data to the new provider, subject to the requirements of the GDPR and associated legislation.

If we provide information to a third party (either a provider of a product or service, or an external data processing agency such as a mailing house) or a company Saga has a legal interest in, we will exercise the strictest control over them contractually, requiring it and any of its agents and/or suppliers to:

  * maintain the security and confidentiality of the information and restrict access to those of its own employees
  * use the data for the agreed purpose only and prevent it being used for any other purpose by any other party
  * refrain from communicating with you other than concerning the product in question
  * return the data to us at the conclusion of any contract term, and destroy or delete any copies made of all or any part of the information unless copies are needed to be kept to comply with regulations

In addition, we will restrict the information disclosed to the absolute minimum necessary, for example, to provide the product or service.

Information sent outside the EEA

We provide products and services including holidays outside the EEA. Therefore, if you travel on such holidays the information you provide may occasionally be transferred outside the EEA. From time to time Saga may use service providers and organisations outside the EEA for the purpose of processing services, system testing and maintenance.

It is worth noting, however, that some non-EEA countries do not afford the same level of data security as the UK. We will always use every reasonable effort to ensure sufficient protections are in place to safeguard your personal information.

**Back to top**

### Amendment and retention of information

Please advise us in writing as to any changes in your circumstances, or if you feel we hold inaccurate information about you so that we can update our records accordingly. 

We will hold your personal information in accordance with the principles of the GDPR (and associated legislation) and in line with our Data Retention Policy. We are obliged and permitted by law and regulation to retain certain types of data for a minimum period of time. The minimum period of time tends to be for six years but can be longer if the statute or regulation requires.

**Back to top**

### Your rights

Access to your information: You have a statutory right of access to accessible personal and/or sensitive personal data that we hold about you. In order to exercise this right, your application must be in writing, either via letter or email. Please refer to the information you wish to see giving dates if possible. Please note that where relevant we may ask for proof of your identity.

We will not administer Subject Access Requests by a third party unless accompanied by a written authority of the individual who is the subject of the request.

We have one month to respond to a valid request.

Rights related to automated decision making including profiling: We use the information we know about you to make decisions which inform our pricing, fraud prevention and the products and services we can offer. Automated decision making enables us to make efficient and fair decisions, providing a better service for our customers. Whilst you have the right to object to us using your information in this way, this could have an impact on the products or services we may be able to offer you. We use automated decision making in the following areas:

Pricing – the information we know and collect about you is used to inform decisions around what we charge for the products and services that we offer. For example, If you apply for insurance, we will compare what you tell us with other records to work out how likely you are to make a claim. This will help us decide whether to offer you the product and what price to charge you.

Tailoring our marketing communications – as mentioned previously, we use your personal information to make decisions about what products, services and offers we think you may be interested in. This ensures the communications you receive from us are tailored and relevant to your interests. You can opt out of this at any time by contacting the Data Protection Officer.

The right to erasure: you have the right to request that your personal data is erased and to prevent processing in specific circumstances which are detailed by the ICO.

The right to data portability: you have the right to obtain and reuse the personal data that you have provided to us for your own purposes which includes transferring it to other services.

For further information regarding your rights, or to make a request; please write to the Data Protection Officer at The Saga Building, Enbrook Park, Sandgate, Kent CT20 3SE or email [data.protection@saga.co.uk](mailto:data.protection@saga.co.uk).

**Back to top**

### Updates to our privacy policy and your comments

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will update all relevant documentation and post any changes on our websites so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

We welcome your questions and comments about privacy. Please write to The Group Data Protection Officer, The Saga Building, Enbrook Park, Sandgate, Kent CT20 3SE or email [data.protection@saga.co.uk](mailto:data.protection@saga.co.uk)

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) if you feel your personal information has not been handled correctly. You can do this via [ico.org.uk/concerns](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/) or by writing to: Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF

**Back to top**

### Use of cookies 

From offers and promotions to sound and video, the aim of this site is to be interesting, helpful and informative. We’re keen to find out what you like and dislike – your feedback plays a key role in helping us improve this site. We use many techniques to follow your use of the site and provide you with a customised experience. The main and best-known technique is by using what are known as 'cookies'.

**What are cookies?** Cookies are small data files that a website will put on your device. Some of these sends information back to the website. They cannot affect your device, but they can collect information that can be used to enhance the site. For example, a cookie can remember the items that you have placed into your shopping basket, or it can ensure you get the offer you requested. These are known as ‘session’ cookies, which expire as soon as you leave the site. Other cookies can tell us if you come back. These are ‘persistent cookies’, which expire 3 years after your last visit unless you delete them from your device. We use them to customise the site – to do things such as display relevant information during your visit. Some cookies enable sites to work, while others help us learn about what people are browsing for.

**How we use cookies**

We use cookies to ensure you get the most from your visit. They improve your experience of the site because certain features work best with cookies. Feedback and information from the cookies can also help make the site better. By visiting this site, you agree to our use of cookies and other technologies. Rest assured that the cookies we use do not store personal details, such as payment card numbers. Here are the main types of cookies and what they do:

**1\. Strictly necessary**  
**In brief** These cookies enable you to get the information or service you’ve asked for. They’re essential – without them, some services may not work.

**For example** We use these cookies to enable you to use shopping baskets, which remember your choices and enable you to buy.

**2\. Performance cookies**  
**In brief** These cookies collect information about the pages you visit, where you go most often and whether you see error messages. The information is only used to ensure a website works well.

**For example** We gather information to diagnose problems and issues. We then use it to make improvements and fix errors.

**3\. Functional cookies**  
**In brief** These cookies remember choices you’ve made to personalise the site. They may remember where you are so you can get tailored information, or remember changes you have made to help you browse, such as increasing the text size.

**For example** If you ask for services based on your location, we sometimes store a cookie so that next time you visit you won’t have to tell us again.

**4\. Targeting or advertising cookies**  
**In brief** These cookies collect information about your browsing habits which are then used to supply you with targeted and personalised on and offline advertising and marketing. They remember if you have visited a website and share this information with advertisers. They enable us to ensure that the content we provide on our site, is aligned to your browsing habits. For example to remind you of products and services that you have shown an interest in.

**For example** These may be used anonymously by third parties to serve advertisements on our behalf across the internet based on your interaction with Saga's website through cookies, quizzes and other technologies. This information may be used by us and our third parties to analyse and track data, as well as to deliver advertising, marketing and content that is based on your interests, including which adverts or content to limit you seeing/ receiving as your browsing history suggests you have no interest in them. These services are provided on Saga's websites or by our carefully selected and monitored partners, and we are committed to ensuring any information is used appropriately.

**Links to other sites**

We often link off to other sites to help provide you with extra information or services. For example, to make it easy for you to share information with your family and friends, we provide links to Twitter, Facebook and other popular social media or book-marking sites. But remember, these sites may use cookies that we do not control. So be sure to check how they use your information.

**How you can control cookies**

If cookies are disabled on your device you will still be able to use most of this site. However, it may limit what you can do.

How you manage your cookies depends on your browser. To find out which browser you use:

  * **PC:** open your browser and go to the **Help** menu and then click on the **About** option.
  * **Apple Macintosh:** open your browser and go to the **Apple** menu and then click on the **About** option.
  * **Mobile device:** check your settings.

If you would prefer to restrict or block cookies and/or delete any you may already have, then follow the how-to guide, which covers the most popular browsers, below:

  * **How to accept cookies**
  * **How to delete cookies**
  * **Mobile and Tablet accepting and deleting cookies**

If you would like to know more about cookies you can visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which explains in detail how they can work and can be managed.

**How to accept cookies**

**Internet Explorer 8.0**

  1. Click on the **Tools** menu in Internet Explorer and select **Internet Options**.
  2. Click on the **Privacy** tab. There are 2 options on how much you want to restrict cookies: 
    1. **Automatic cookie handling** – Set the slider to **Medium** to enable cookies on most websites
    2. **Restrict to selective sites** – Set slider to **High** and select the **Sites** button and enter in[www.saga.co.uk](http://www.saga.co.uk/) in the text field and then click the Allow button then the **OK** button.
  3. Click on the **OK** button to save settings.

**Internet Explorer 9.0 – 11.0**

  1. Click on the **Gear icon** in the top right hand corner of the browser window and click on **Internet Options**.
  2. Click on the **Privacy** Tab. There are 2 options on how much you want to restrict cookies: 
    1. **Automatic cookie handling** – Set the slider to **Medium** to enable cookies on most websites.
    2. **Restrict to selective sites** – Set slider to **High** and select the **Sites** button and enter in [www.saga.co.uk](http://www.saga.co.uk/) in the text field and then click the **Allow** button then the **OK** button.
  3. Click on the **OK** button to save settings.

**Firefox 26.0 and newer**

  1. Click the **icon depicting three horizontal lines** in the top-right corner and select **Options**.
  2. Click on the **Privacy** tab. There are 2 options on how much you want to restrict cookies: 
    1. **No Restriction** – Select from the dropdown **Remember History**.
    2. **Restrict to selective sites** – Select from the dropdown to **Use Custom settings for history**. Tick **Accept cookies from sites**.
  3. Click the **OK** button to save settings.

**Chrome 10 – 22**

  1. From the browser menu choose the **Spanner** icon
  2. Then **Settings**
  3. Click **Under the Bonnet**
  4. In **Privacy** click **Content settings**
  5. In **Cookies** choose the radio button **Allow local data to be set.**

**Chrome 31 and Newer**

  1. Click the **icon depicting three horizontal lines** in the top-right corner and select **Settings**.
  2. Click on **Show advanced Settings** … at the bottom of the page.
  3. In the section entitled **Privacy** click the button **Content Settings…** There 2 options: 
    1. **Automatic cookie handling** – In the section entitled **Cookies** select the option **Allow local to be set**.
    2. **Add exceptions manually** – Click the **Manage exceptions…** button. In the column titled **Hostname pattern** type [www.saga.co.uk](http://www.saga.co.uk/) into the text box and select **Allow** and click **Done**.
  4. Click on **Done** to save settings.

**Safari 5.0 (Apple Macintosh and PC Windows)**

  1. From the menu choose **Safari**
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the **Security** **** icon and then Show cookies
  4. Choose to accept cookies Always or Only from sites I visit

**Safari 5.1 (Apple Macintosh)**

  1. From the menu choose **Safari**
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the **Privacy** icon
  4. For the option **Block cookies** : choose **Never** or else **From third parties and advertisers**

**Safari 5.1.5 (PC Windows)**

  1. From the browser menu choose the **Cog wheel** icon
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the **Privacy** icon
  4. For the option **Block cookies** : choose **Never** or else **From third parties and advertisers**

Back to top ****

**How to delete cookies**

To remove cookies follow the steps in this section. Do not try to edit the cookies file on your computer.

**Internet Explorer 8.0**

  1. From the menu choose **Tools**
  2. Then **Internet Options**
  3. On the **General tab** , under Browsing history click Settings
  4. Click **View files**
  5. Click the **Name** column heading to alphabetically sort the files
  6. Scroll down to files that begin with the prefix **cookie** : – all cookies have this prefix, and they usually contain the name of the website that created the cookie
  7. **Right-click** **** to delete a cookie you want to remove
  8. Close the window, then click **OK** twice to return to the browser window

**Internet Explorer 9.0 – 11.0**

  1. Click on the **Gear icon** in the top right hand corner of the browser window and click on **Internet Options**.
  2. In the **General Tab** under the **Browsing history section** click on the **Delete** button.
  3. Within the pop up window tick the **Cookies and website data** **** and click on the **Delete** Button.
  4. Click the **Apply** button to save settings.

**Firefox 26.0 and Newer**

  1. Click the ******icon depicting three horizontal lines** in the top-right corner and select **Options**.
  2. Click on the **Privacy** tab, under the History section click on **clear your recent history link in blue**.
  3. From the pop up window select **Everything** in the dropdown and click the **Clear Now** button.
  4. Click the **OK** button to exit.

**Chrome 10 - 22**

  1. From the browser menu choose the **Spanner** icon
  2. Then **Settings**
  3. Click **Under the Bonnet**
  4. In **Privacy** **** click **Content settings**
  5. In **Cookies** click the button **All cookies and site data**
  6. Select a site from the list and click **X**

**Chrome 31 and Newer**

  1. Click the **icon depicting three horizontal lines** in the top-right corner and select **Settings**.
  2. Click on **Show Advanced Settings…** at the bottom of the page.
  3. In the section entitled **Privacy** click the button **Clear Browsing Data…**
  4. From the pop up window in the drop down select **the beginning of time** and tick the **Cookies and other site and plug-in data**.
  5. Click the **Clear Browsing data** button to remove cookies.

**Safari 5.0 (Apple Macintosh)**

  1. From the menu choose **Safari**
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the Security icon and then **Show Cookies**
  4. Select a cookie from the list and click **Remove**
  5. To delete all cookies click **Remove All**

**Safari 5.1 (Apple Macintosh)**

  1. From the menu choose **Safari**
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the **Privacy** icon and then **Details**
  4. Select a cookie from the list and click **Remove**
  5. To delete all cookies click **Remove All**

**Safari 5.0 (PC Windows)**

  1. From the menu choose **Edit**
  2. Then **Preferences**
  3. Click the **Security** icon and then **Show Cookies**
  4. Select a cookie from the list and click the **Remove** button
  5. To delete all cookies click **Remove All**

**Safari 5.1.5 and Newer** ******(PC Windows)**

  1. Click on the **Gears icon** in the right hand corner of the window.
  2. Select **Reset Safari** and tick **Remove all website data**.
  3. Click the **Reset** button to remove cookies.

If you are not using any of the above browsers, then select 'cookies' in the 'Help' function for information on where to find your cookie folder.

**Mobile and Tablet accepting and deleting cookies**

These are only for the built in browsers on phones and tablets. Please refer to the help menu for all other browsers.

**iPad/iPhone accepting cookies**

  1. Go to the **Home screen** by pressing the **Home** button.
  2. Select the **Settings icon** and select **Safari** from the Settings Menu.
  3. Select **Block Cookies** from the Safari menu and then from the drop down select **Always Allow** and select the **tick icon** to save.
  4. Press **Home** button to exit.

**iPad/iPhone deleting cookies**

  1. Go to the **Home screen** by pressing the **Home** button.
  2. Select the **Settings icon** and select **Safari** from the Settings Menu.
  3. Select **Clear Cookies** and from the pop up click on **Clear**.
  4. Press **Home** button to exit.

**Samsung Tab accepting cookies**

  1. Open the **Browser** and select the **Menu** button.
  2. Select the **Gear Settings option**. Scroll to the **Privacy Settings** section.
  3. Tick the **Accept Cookies** option.
  4. Select the **Home** button to exit.

**Samsung Tab deleting cookies**

  1. Open the **browser** and select the **Menu** button.
  2. Select the **Gear Settings option**. Scroll to the **Privacy Settings** section.
  3. Select the **Clear all cookie data** and select **Yes**.
  4. Select the **Home** **** button to exit.

**Samsung phones accepting cookies**

  1. Open the **inbuilt browser** and open a **new tab**.
  2. Select the **3 dots icon** on the right hand corner of the screen and select **Settings**.
  3. Under the **Advanced section** select **Content Settings**.
  4. Under the **Content settings section** tick the **Accept cookies**.
  5. Select the **Home** button to exit.

**Samsung phones deleting cookies**

  1. Open the **inbuilt browser** and open a **new tab**.
  2. Select the **3 dots icon** on the right hand corner of the screen and select **Settings**.
  3. Under the **Advanced section** select **Content Settings**.
  4. Under the **Reset Settings** select **Reset settings** and select OK.
  5. Select the **Home** button to exit.

**Windows phone accepting cookies**

  1. Open **Internet Explorer** and press **3 dot icon** and select **Settings**.
  2. Tick the **Allow cookies on my phone**.

**Windows phone deleting cookies**

  1. Open **Internet Explorer** and press **3 dot icon** and select **Settings**.
  2. Select **Delete history** and select **OK**.

**Windows Surface accepting cookies**

  1. Open **Internet Explorer** and swipe in the right to get the **Charms Bar**.
  2. Tap the **Spanner icon** to show the settings and select **Options**.
  3. Under the **Privacy section** and tick **Allow Cookies**.

**Windows Surface deleting cookies**

  1. Open **Internet Explorer** and swipe in the right to get the **Charms Bar**.
  2. Tap the **Spanner icon** to show the settings and select **Options**.
  3. Under the **History section** select the button to delete.
  4. Select **Cookies** to delete and tap delete.

**Back to top**
